Preliminary Guide to the New Haven Redevelopment Agency Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Office of Public Information, Series XV
  - Subject files
    - Audio [masters only] (Box 300)
      Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Scrapbooks
      - 1955 (Box 301)
      - 1956 (Box 301A)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 302)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 303)
      - 1959-1961, 1963 (Box 304)
      - 1963 (Box 305)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 306)
      - 1965 (Box 307)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 308)
      - Appleby and Citizens Action Committee (Box 309)
      - Logue (Box 310)
      - Worcester, Alms, Grand (Box 311)
- Open Space Program, Series XVI
  - General (Box 312–318)
- Printed, Series XVII
  - General (Box 319–329)
- Projects, Series XVIII
  - Projects Overall
    - Management grant 701, contracts, demolition (Box 330)
    - Demolition, developers, disposition (Box 331)
    - Disposition, financial, housing (Box 332)
    - Housing (Box 333–334)
    - Housing; Housing Now in New Haven, Inc.; Section 8; Section 10(C) and 23; Sections 221(d)(3), 235, 236 (Box 335)
    - Sections 221(d)(3); 235; 236; housing publications; job seekers (Box 336)
    - Job seekers, labor (Box 337)
    - Urban renewal, property management (Box 338)
    - Property management (Box 339–340)
    - Rehabilitation (Box 341)
    - Relocation (Box 342–343)
    - Relocation, reports (Box 344)
    - Reports, transcripts, utilities (Box 345)
    - Zoning, affirmative action (Box 346)
    - Financial [mostly reports] (Box 347–350)
  - Church Street
    - Acquisition and condemnation, capital improvements (Box 351)
    - Capital improvements (Box 352–359)
    - Contracts (Box 360–364)
    - Contracts, disposition and developers (Box 365)
    - Disposition and developers (Box 366)
    - Disposition (Box 367–388)
    - Financial (Box 389–390)
    - Financial, project planning and plan amendments (Box 391)
    - Project planning and plan amendments (Box 392–396)
    - Property management (Box 397–398)
    - Utility relocation (Box 399–400)
  - Dixwell
    - Acquisitions and condemnation (Box 401)
    - Capital improvements (Box 402–405)
    - Capital improvements, contracts (Box 406)
    - Contracts (Box 407–408)
    - Contracts, demolition, disposition (Box 409)
    - Disposition (Box 410)
    - Disposition parcels
      - 1-A, B, C, C (Florence Virtue Homes) (Box 411)
      - 1-F (Dixwell shopping center) (Box 412–414)
      - 1-F, 2 (Box 415)
      - 2 (Box 416)
      - 5 and 62, 6, 7-10, 18, 20, 21 (Box 417)
      - 21, 22 (Box 418)
      - 22, 23, 24, 25 and 37, 27, 28, 29 (Box 419)
      - 30, 31 and 32, 34, 35, 36, 37 (Box 420)
      - 38, 39, 40, 49, 41, 42, 43, 44, 43, 44, 44a, 44b, 44c, 45, 46 (Box 421)
      - 47a, 47b, 48, 50, 51, 52, 53, 54 (Box 422)
      - 52, 53, 54, 54a, 55a, 55b, 56, 57, 58, 60a (Box 423)
      - 60, 60-B, 61, 63, 64, 65, 66-A, 66-B, 67, 68, 69, 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75 (Box 424)
      - 76, 77, 78, 79, 80, 81, 82, 83, 84-A, 84-B (Box 425)
    - Financial (Box 425)
    - Financial (Box 426)
    - Financial, project closing, project litigation, project planning (Box 427)
    - Project planning (Box 428–431)
    - Project planning, property management (Box 432)
    - Property management, relocation (Box 433)
    - Relocation, utilities (Box 434)
    - Dixwell Community House-neighborhood facilities (Box 435–437)
    - Dixwell Community House-neighborhood facilities, Julie Billiart neighborhood facility (St. Martin's Church) (Box 438)
  - Dwight
    - Acquisitions and condemnation (Box 439)
    - Acquisitions and condemnation, capital improvements and contracts (Box 440)
    - Capital improvements and contracts (Box 441–442)
    - Capital improvements and contracts, contracts (Box 443)
    - Contracts (Box 444–445)
    - Demolition (Box 446)
    - Disposition
      - General
      - Housing
      - Parcels
        - A-1-A, S-18, A-1-B, A-2, A-2-A
        - A-2, A-2-A, A-2-B, C, D (Box 447)
        - A-2-B, C, D, A-2-E, A-2-F, A-3, A-3-A, S-6-A, S-6-B, A-4 (Box 448)
        - A-4 (Box 449)
        - A-5, A-6, A-6-A, A-6-B, A-7-A through A-7-L (Box 450)
        - A-7-A through A-7-L, A-7-A, A-7-B, A-7-C, A-7-D, A-7-E, A-7-F, A-7-G, A-7-H, A-7-J (Box 451)
        - A-7-J-A, A-7-K and A-7-L, A-8, B-1, B-2 (Box 452)
        - B-2-A, B-2-B, B-5 (Box 453)
        - S-1, S-2-A,B, S-3-A (Box 454)
        - S-3-A, S-3-B, S-4 (Box 455)
        - S-4, S-5-A, S-5-B, S-6, S-7-A (Box 456)
        - S-7-A, S-7-B, 8-B, S-9, S-10, S-11, S-12 (Box 457)
        - S-12, S-13, S-14, S-15, S-16, S-16-A through S-16-F, S-17, S-18 and A-1, S-19, S-20 (Box 458)
    - Financial (Box 459)
    - Financial, legal, project planning (Box 460)
    - Project planning (Box 461–466)
  - Economic development
    - Long Wharf (Box 467)
    - General (Box 468)
    - South Industrial Boulevard Park (Box 469–470)
    - Projects overall (Box 471–474)
  - Fair Haven
    - Acquisitions (Box 475)
    - Acquisitions, condemnation, capital improvements and contracts (Box 476)
    - Capital improvements and contracts (Box 477–478)
    - Capital improvements and contracts, contracts (Box 479)
    - Contracts (Box 480–483)
    - Demolition (Box 484)
    - Developers (Box 484)
    - Disposition
      - Parcels
        - A-1, A-2, A-4, A-5, B-1, B-1-A, B-1 through B-8, C-1
        - Brewery Square, B-3, C-2, C-2-A, C-2-B, C-3, C-2-E, C-2-F, C-3, C-4-A, C-4-B, C-2-C, C-4 and C-5, C-6, C-6A, C-6-B, C-7, C-8, S-1, S-12, S-23, S-36, S-47, S-35, C-5, S-2, S-5, S-11B, S-37, S-55, S-1, S-2, S-3, S-4, S-6, S-7, S-8, S-9, S-11-A, S-22, S-23, S-31, S-10, S-11-B, S-12, S-13, S-14, S-15, S-17B (Box 485)
        - S-17-C, S-17-E, S-17-G, S-19, S-16, S-17-G, S-18, S-20, S-20-A, S-20-B, S-21, S-22, S-23, S-23-A, S-25, S-27, S-24, S-26, S-29, S-28, S-30, S-31, S-32, S-32-A, S-32-B, S-34, S-35, C-5, S-38, S-36, S-38-A, S-40, S-41-A, S-41-B, S-42, S-43, S-44, S-45, S-46-A, S-46-B, S-48-A, S-48-B, S-52, S-49 (Box 486)
    - Financial (Box 487–488)
    - Project closing, project planning, public hearings (Box 489)
    - Public hearings (Box 490)
    - Public hearings, rehabilitation (Box 491)
    - Rehabilitation (Box 492)
    - Zoning, property management, relocation, utilities (Box 493)
  - Hill
    - Adeline-Asylum (Box 494)
    - Auburn-Columbus Avenue (Box 495)
    - Columbus Avenue-Davenport (Box 496)
    - Davenport-Frank (Box 497)
    - Gilbert-Howard (Box 498)
    - Howard-Kimberly (Box 499)
    - Kimberly-Morris (Box 500)
    - Orchard-Putnam (Box 501)
    - Redfield (Box 502)
    - Acquisitions (Box 503)
    - Acquisitions, capital improvements and contracts (Box 504)
    - Capital improvements (Box 505)
    - Capital improvements and contracts, contracts (Box 506)
    - Contracts (Box 507–510)
    - Demolition (Box 511)
    - Disposition parcels
      - A-3-C, A-3-D, A-3-E, A-8-2
      - A-3-A, A-3-B, A-3-C, A-3-D, A-3-E, A-3-C, D, E, F, S-24, A-3-F-A, A-3-G, A-3-H, A-3-I, A-3-J, A-3-K, A-15, A-12, A-25, A-26, B-7, B-22, B-12, A-13-A, A-22-A, A-23-B, A-23-C, A-23-E, A-23-A, B-1, B-1-A, B-1-B, B-1-C, B-2-A, B-2-A-1, B-2-B, B-4, B-14, C-7, S-4, B-18-B, S-5, S-6, S-7, S-8, S-13, S-16-A (Box 512)
      - S-16-B, S-21, S-22, S-24-A, S-24-B, S-26, S-30, S-34, S-35, S-37, S-36, S-37-A, S-38, S-39, S-40, S-41, S-42-A, s-43, S-44, S-45, S-46-A, S-46-B, S-48, S-49, S-50, S-51, S-53, S-42-B, S-54, S-57, S-58, S-59, S-61, S-58-A, S-64, S-65, S-66, S-67, S-71-A (Box 513)
      - S-72, S-73, S-74-A, S-75-A, S-76, S-78-A, S-80-B (Box 514)
    - Financial (Box 514)
    - Financial (Box 515)
    - Financial, litigation (Box 516)
    - Project planning (Box 517–523)
    - Project planning, project management, relocation (Box 524)
    - Relocation (Box 525)
    - Interim assistance program (Box 526)
    - Interim assistance program, model cities program (Box 527)
    - Model cities (Box 528–529)
  - Long Wharf
    - Acquisitions (Box 530)
    - Capital improvements (Box 531–532)
    - Capital improvements, contracts (Box 533)
    - Contracts (Box 534)
    - Contracts, state assistance (Box 535)
    - State assistance (Box 536)
    - Developers (Box 536)
    - Disposition parcels
      - Albie Booth Boys Club, Long Wharf Association, A, G, G-1, H
      - Sargent Co, A, B, B-1, B-3 (Box 537)
      - B, B-1, B-1, C (Box 538)
      - B-1 (Box 539)
      - B-1, B-2-B, B-3 (Box 540)
      - B-3, B-3-A, B-3-B, B, B-3-D, D (Box 541)
      - D, E, G, G-1, G, G-1, H (Box 542)
      - G, G-1, H, H-1, J, H, K, L (Box 543)
      - L-1, SA-1, SA-1, SA-2, SA-2 (Box 544)
    - Financial (Box 545–547)
    - Financial, agency resolutions (Box 548)
    - Project planning, public hearings (Box 549)
    - Public hearings (Box 550)
    - Public hearings, rehabilitation, reports, property management (Box 551)
    - Relocation, utilities, zoning (Box 552)
  - Newhallville
    - Acquisitions, condemnation (Box 553)
    - Condemnation (Box 553)
    - New Haven Railroad (Box 553)
    - New Haven Railroad, capital improvements, non-cash grant-in-aid, individual project files (Box 554)
    - Individual project files, contracts (Box 555)
    - Public hearings, ELA loan amendments (Box 556)
    - ELA loan amendments (Box 557)
    - ELA loan amendments, project area committee, Sauer's housing program, contracts, demolition, developers (Box 558)
    - Developers (Box 559)
    - Housing (Box 559)
    - Disposition parcels
      - A-2, Sherman Avenue and Munson Street
      - A-3, 4, A-6, B-2, B-3, A-7, A-8, A-9, A-10, A-11, B -2, B-3, B-4, B-5, S-1, S-2, S-3, S-4, S-5, S-6, S-7, S-9, S-10, S-11, S-12, S-13, A-13-A, S-14, S-15 (Box 560)
      - S-17, S-18, S-19, S-20, S-21, S-22, S-23, S-24, S-26, S-28, S-29, S-30, S-32, S-39 (Box 561)
    - Financial, budgets, S&P budgets, project expenditures/budgets, cost reports and balance sheets (Box 561)
    - Project financial, public hearings (Box 562)
    - Public hearings, minor modifications to plan, public hearings, maps, neighborhood participation (Box 563)
  - Oak Street
    - Acquisitions, condemnation (Box 564)
    - Condemnation, capital improvements and contracts (Box 565)
    - Appraisals, contracts (Box 566)
    - Contracts (Box 567)
    - Demolition, disposition, developers, parcels A, B, C, disposition (Box 568)
    - Disposition (Box 569–570)
    - Crown Tower parcel A, Crown Court parcel B (Box 571–572)
    - Crown Tower parcel A, Crown Court parcel B, disposition (Box 573)
    - Disposition (Box 574)
    - Disposition, financial (Box 575)
    - Financial (Box 576)
    - Project planning (Box 577)
    - Project planning, public information, amendments to plan (Box 578)
    - Amendments to plan, project planning (Box 579)
    - Project planning, property management (Box 580)
    - Property management, relocation (Box 581)
    - Relocation (Box 582)
  - State Street
    - Acquisitions and condemnation (Box 583–584)
    - Capital improvements and contracts (Box 585–588)
    - Contracts (Box 589–592)
    - Contracts, demolition, disposition-general (Box 593)
    - Disposition-general (Box 594)
    - Disposition parcels
      - Block A, A-1 (Box 595)
      - A-2, A-3, A-1, A-3, A-3-A, A-2, A-3, A-4, A-5 (Box 596)
      - A-5, A-6, A-6-A, A-7, A-8, A-9 (Box 597)
      - A-9, A-10, A-11, A-10, A-11, B-1, B-1-A (Box 598)
      - B-1, B-1-A, C (Box 599)
      - C (Box 600–603)
      - C, D, D-1, D-1-A, D-1-B, D-2 (Box 604)
      - D-2, E, E-1, E-2, E-3 (Box 605)
      - E-3, E-4, F, G, H, I, I-1, I-2, J-1, Q, R. K, L, M, N, O, R-1, R-2 (Box 606)
    - Financial (Box 607)
    - Financial, project planning (Box 608)
    - Project planning (Box 609–613)
    - Property management (Box 614–618)
  - Temple George garage
    - Acquisitions, capital improvements and contracts, contracts, demolition, developers, disposition parcels A, A-1 (Box 619)
    - Disposition parcels A-1-B, A-1, A-1-C, financial (Box 620)
    - Financial, project closing, public hearings (Box 621)
    - Public hearings, property management, relocation (Box 622)
  - Wooster Square
    - Acquisitions and condemnation (Box 623–624)
    - Acquisitions and condemnation, capital improvements and contracts (Box 625)
    - Capital improvements and contracts (Box 626–630)
    - Capital improvements and contracts, contracts (Box 631)
    - Contracts (Box 632–635)
    - Legal counsel, state assistance, negotiations, planning, surveys, title search (Box 636)
    - Demolition (Box 637)
    - Disposition parcels
      - A-1, A-3, A-6, A-6-A
      - A-6-A, A-6-B, A-6-C, A-7, A-8 (Box 638)
      - A-8, A-9, A-10 (Box 639)
      - A-11 (Box 640)
      - A-11, A-12 (Box 641)
      - B-1, B-2, B-2-B, B-3, B-3-A, B-3-A&B, B-3-C, B-4-A, B-4-B, B-5-A, B-5-B (Box 642)
      - B-5-B, B-5-6, B-6, B-6-A, B-7, B-7-A, B-7-B, B-8 (Box 643)
      - B-9, B-10-A, B-10-A and B-10-C, B-11, B-12, B-12-A (Box 644)
      - B-12-B, B-12-C, B-12-D, B-12-E (Box 645)
      - B-12-E, B-12-F, B-12-G, B-12-G-2 (Box 646)
      - B-12-G-2, B-14, B-14-A, B-14-B, B-14-C, B-15-B&A, B-16, B-17 (Box 647)
      - B-17, B-18-A&B, B-18-B, B-19 (Box 648)
      - B-19, C-1, C-1-A, C-1-B, C-1-C, C-1-D, C-1-F, C-1-H (Box 649)
      - C-1-H, C-1-K, C-1-L, C-1-M (Box 650)
      - C-1-N, C-1-O, C-1-P, C-1-R, C-1-T (Box 651)
      - C-2, C-2 and C-3, C-3, C-3-A, c-4 (Box 652)
      - C-5, C-5-A, C-5-B, C-6. C-6-A, C-6-B, C-7, C-7-A (Box 653)
      - C-7-A, C-7-B, C-7-C, C-7-D, C-7-E (Box 654)
      - C-7-E, C-7-F, C-7-G, C-7-H, C-8, C-8-A, C-8-B, C-8-C (Box 655)
      - C-8-B and C-8-C, C-8-D, C-10, C-10-A&B, C-11-A (Box 656)
      - C-11-B, C-12 and C-7-H, C-14-A, C-14-B, C-15-A, C-15-B, C-16 and C-17, C-18, C-19 (Box 657)
      - C-19, C-20-A, C-20-B, C-20-A through Court Street houses (Box 658)
      - Court Street houses (Box 659)
      - Court Street houses, S-1, S-2, S-3, S-4, S-5-B, S-16-B, S-22-B, S-2, S-3, S-4, S-5 and S-5-A, S-5-B, S-6, S-7 (Box 660)
      - S-8, S-9 throuogh S-14, S-8, S-9, S-12-A, S-12-B, S-15, S-16, S-16-A, S-16-B, S-17-A (Box 661)
      - S-17, S-17, S-18, S-18-A, S-17-B, S-19-A-1, 2, 3, S-19-A-1, S-19-A-2 (Box 662)
      - S-19-A-2, S-19-A-3, S-19-A-4, S-19-A-5, S-19-B, S-20, S-21, S-22, S-22-B, S-23, S-24, S-25, S-26, S-27 (Box 663)
      - S-27, S-27-A, S-27-B, S-27-C, S-28, S-29 (Box 664)
      - S-30, S-12-B, S-31-A&B, S-32-A&B, S-33, 612 Chapel Street, S-31-A, S-31-B, S-32-A, S-32-A&B, S-32-B (Box 665)
      - S-32-B, S-33, S-38, S-39, S-35-A&B, S-34-A, S-36, S-37-A, S-34-A, S-34-B, S-35-A&B, S-36, 560 and 562 Chapel Street, S-36, S-37 (Box 666)
      - S-37, S-38, s-39, S-40 (Box 667)
    - Financial (Box 667)
    - Financial (Box 668)
    - Financial, project planning (Box 669)
    - Project planning (Box 670–672)
    - Project planning, property management (Box 673)
    - Property management (Box 674)
    - Relocation (Box 675–676)
- Regional Water Authority, Series XIX
  - General files (Box 677–678)
- Reuse Parcel Survey Maps, Series XX
  - R-1 [Wooster Square]
    - Parcels
      - A-1 through A-14, B-2 through B-14 (Box 679)
      - B-14 through B-19, C-1 through C-20, S-1 through S-18 (Box 680)
      - S-19-A-1 through S-35 (Box 681)
    - Rehabilitation houses, miscellaneous maps (Box 681)
  - R-2 [Church Street] (Box 681)
  - R-2 [Church Street] (Box 682)
  - R-20 parcels [Dixwell]
    - 1-6 (Box 682)
    - 6-7, S-21 through S-79 (Box 683)
  - R-28 parcels [State Street]
    - A through A-1, A-4, A-6 (Box 683)
    - A-1 through T-14 (Box 684)
  - R-71 parcels [Dwight}
    - A-1 through A-7-H (Box 684)
    - A-7-J through Elm Street (Box 685)
  - R-79 parcels [Fair Haven]
    - A-1 through S-14 (Box 685)
    - A-8-1 (Box 686)
  - R-91 [Newhallville], R-96 [Hill Project], Long Wharf (Box 686)
  - Long Wharf (Box 687)
- State of Connecticut, Series XXI
  - State departments and agencies (Box 688–689)
  - State departments and agencies, state legislation (Box 690)
  - State assistance programs (Box 691–693)
  - Connecticut Development Commission (Box 694)
- Taft-Adams, Series XXII
  - General [housing site development] (Box 695)
- Urban Renewal in Other Cities, Series XXIII
  - Other agencies-general, Birmingham, Boston, Columbus, Fresno, Greensboro, Hampton, Little Rock, Manchester, Norfolk, Pittsburgh, San Francisco, Springfield, Washington (Box 696)
- Workable Programs, Series XXIV
  - Applications, correspondence, general, 1954-1966 (Box 697)
- Card Files, Series XXV
  - Card files [contain address information] (Box 698–700)
- Minutes, 1959-1995; Series XXVI
  - Regular meetings
    - 1956-1959 (Box 701)
    - 1960 (Box 702)
    - 1962 (Box 703)
    - 1963 (Box 704)
    - 1964 (Box 705)
    - 1965 (Box 706)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 707)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 708)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 709)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 710)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 711)
    - 1978 (Box 712)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 713)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 714)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 715)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 716)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 717)
  - Regular/special meetings
    - 1986-1988, September (Box 718)
    - 1988, October-1989 (Box 719)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 720)
    - 1992-1995 (Box 721)
  - Executive meetings
    - 1966-1967 (Box 722)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 723)
    - 1971-1972, 1974 (Box 724)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 725)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 726)
    - 1981-1985, 1990, May-1991, December (Box 727)
  - Audio tapes of meetings [masters only] (Box 728)
- Projects, Miscellaneous, Series XXVII
  - Ninth Square
    - Chapel (Box 729)
    - Church, Crown (Box 730)
    - Phase I Environmental Assessment, Crown (Box 731)
    - George, Orange property appraisals (Box 732)
    - Orange, State property appraisals (Box 733)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 734–735)
  - Middletown Avenue, Career High School (Box 736)
  - State Street, Arts Center, Long Wharf (Box 737)
  - Long Wharf (Box 738)
  - State Street (Box 739)
  - State Street, Boulevard Municipal Development Authority, Orphan Bridge Project (Box 740)
  - Airport, Mill River Industrial Park (Box 741)
  - Quinnipiac River Industrial and Business Development Plan (Box 742)
  - Quinnipiac (Box 743)
  - West River (Box 744–745)
  - West River, Fair Haven, Tax Foreclosures (Box 746)
  - Bulky Waste Site, Taubman Mall, Condemnations Open (Box 747)
  - Condemnations Open (Box 748–749)
- Miscellaneous, Series XXVIII
  - A-B (Box 750)
  - C-G (Box 751)
  - G-L (Box 752)
  - L-P (Box 753)
  - Q-S (Box 754)
  - S (Box 755)
  - S-W (Box 756)
  - W (Box 757)
  - Unordered (Box 758–760)
  - 1980s (Box 761)
- Additional Material, Accession 2006-M-007
  Scope and Contents
  This accession contains materials used in the preparation of Historical Documentation: New Haven Veterans Memorial Coliseum, a publication prepared for the Office of Economic Development, New Haven.
  - Historical Documentation: New Haven Veterans Memorial Coliseum, 2005 July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of the Coliseum, [2005] (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Compact disc #1, text of publication and scanned photographs, [2005] (Box 2)
    Original computer files, as well as preservation masters, may not be played.
  - Compact disc #2, original architectural and structural plans, [2005] (Box 3)